getvideostream.com 2019-09-27

# Groupnotes Inc. dba Videostream, Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

RouteThis Inc. (operating as "Videostream" and hereinafter referred to as "Videostream"/"we"/"us"/"our") is committed to protecting your privacy. Videostream provides video playback services through our proprierty software, website, mobile apps, and web application ("App", collectively, the "Services") for our customers ("Customers") and end-users ("End Users", collectively with the Customers "Users"). This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, store, use and share information collected through the website http://Videostream.com/ ("Website") and the Services about visitors to the Website, Customers and End Users. Customers and website visitors are collectively referred to herein as "you". This Privacy Policy does not apply to our Customers' use of personal information; such information is governed by our Customers' privacy practices and policies, and we have no control over and are in no way responsible or liable for Customers' use of personal information. Any capitalized terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning set out in the Videostream Terms of Service. We, Groupnotes Inc., known commonly by users as "Videostream", is the controller of the data that you provide to us (when creating an account or signing up for a newsletter). All references to "we", "us", or "our" in this document should be understood to mean Videostream. 

### Consent:

By using the Website or our Services you consent to the use of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, your Personal Information will not be used for any other purpose without your consent. We will not actively collect Personal Information for the purpose of sale or marketing in a way that specifically identifies the individual. In other words, we don't sell customer lists. You may withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Information at any time. However, withdrawing consent may result in your inability to continue using the Website and/or the Services. 

### What information we collect:

We aim to collect, use and disclose only such information as is required to enable us to provide the Services, to maintain our Customer/visitor lists, to respond to your inquiries or provide feedback, for identification and authentication purposes and for service improvement. We will maintain the confidentiality of any contact information you provide in connection with using our Services or contacting us with questions or for further information and we will use it only for the purposes for which we have collected it (subject to the exclusions and disclosures we have listed below), unless you agree that we may disclose it to other third parties. 

We collect personal information only when given with your consent. Personal information refers to contact information that directly or indirectly tells specifically who you are, such as your name, phone number, company name, job, email, or any other information that could be linked to you with reasonable effort. At Videostream, we only require your email to use our premium services, but other information may be given voluntarily to perform tasks such as remembering settings and sending email communications. 

We do not collect sensitive information such as racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic data, data concerning health, or sexual orientation. 

We may collect data passively as you use our website. This is known as "Usage Data". We and our partners may use this to collect various types of information about you, your computer or other device used to access this site. You may commonly see this when generating a "log file' to help with support issues, but it may take other forms. This kind of data is essentially anonymous when collected, but could be used indirectly to identify a person. 

We provide notifications for certain activities relating to Customers' use of our Services despite Customers' indicated e-mail preferences, for example we may send notices of any updates to our Terms of Use, Service issues or shutdowns, or Privacy Policy. 

You may withdraw your consent for receiving marketing communications by clicking the "unsubscribe" link located within each communication, or contacting us at the email: team@getvideostream.com.

### Why we need and what we do with your information: 

We only collect data that is needed to provide you with the services that Videostream offers and that you pay for. (For example, using Videostream Premium requires that you are logged into Google Chrome or the app with your email account). 

We collect your emails to send you updates, newsletters, and marketing campaigns only when you have explicitly consented to receive this from us. You have the right to contact us to inquire what information we have about you, as well as to ask for this information to be removed. 

As a private-sector organisation, we may process personal data without consent if it benefits us commercially. We will never do this if it causes harm to your individual rights, freedoms, and interests. We process data used for marketing and update communications (such as newsletters) only through your direct consent. 

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

We may share and disclose your personal information and Usage Data as outlined below. You are able to contact us if you wish to opt out of all information sharing with 3rd parties. 

We may provide your personal data and Usage Data to any affiliated entities we may have, including our subsidiaries. Affiliated entities are entities that we legally control or that control us. We may provide access to your personal information and Usage Data to our sub-processors that assist us with the operation and maintenance of this site. For example, we may work with third parties to process payments, host our servers, store analytics and user data, display/parse data, and provide security, among other things. 

If we sell or otherwise transfer part or all of our business or assets to another organization, we may transfer your personal information and Usage Data. In such an event, we will require the buyer or transferee to agree to our commitments provided in this Privacy Policy. 

We will only share your information when deemed absolutely necessary. We will not disclose information about you unless: a) when required by law; b) to comply with legal process; c) to protect interests of Videostream, including but not limited to its physical and intellectual property; d) other situations when deemed necessary. 

### Transfer of Information: 

If you are outside of Canada, you are sending your personal information and Usage Data to Canada where we are located but which be stored and/or processed in other countries where our data storage partners keep servers. That information may be transferred within Canada or to other countries. Your personal information and Usage Data will always be governed by this Privacy Policy. 

### Analytics: 

We may participate with third party analytics partners, including but not limited to Google Analytics and Mixpanel, to monitor and analyze Web traffic and to keep track of user behavior on this site and Services. Google Analytics and Mixpanel are web analysis services provided by Google Inc. ("Google") and Mixpanel, Inc. ("Mixpanel"), respectively. Google and Mixpanel utilize the data collected to track and examine the use of this site, to prepare reports on its activities, and to share them with us and other services to improve our content. The privacy policies of both Google Analytics and Mixpanel, as well as how to opt out, can be found online. 

### Email Communication: 

We may participate with third party mail partners, including but not limited to Mailjet. Mailjet is a service provided by Mailjet Inc. ("Mailjet"). Mailjet holds our mailing lists and is the only permanant storage location of user email addresses for the purpose of marketing communications, privacy updates, etc. and sends emails on behalf of Groupnotes, Inc. 

### Cookies: 

We may automatically collect Usage Data through the use of "cookies". Videostream may issue cookies when you use our site, unless you have activated settings in your browse that stop cookies from being issued. Cookies are small text files that a website uses to recognize users and facilitate ongoing use of the site. Cookies also allow us to track usage behaviour that will allow for improvement to the website. 

### How we store your information: 

We will always store your information in a safe location, accessible only to Videostream (and other Groupnotes Inc.) employees, our trusted sub-processors, and others when deemed necessary or required by law. 

### How long we keep your information: 

We will not retain your personal information for longer than required. This means that we will keep your information for any or a combination of time periods described as follows: (i) for as long as required by law, (ii) until we no longer have a valid reason for keeping it, (iii) until you request us to stop using it. 

### Your rights: 

Under the new GDPR guidelines, you have the right to: 

  * Access information about the processing of your personal data;
  * Obtain access to the personal data held about you;
  * Ask for incorrect, inaccurate or incomplete personal data to be corrected;
  * Request that personal data be erased when it's no longer needed or if processing it is unlawful;
  * Object to the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes or on grounds relating to your particular situation;
  * Request the restriction of the processing of your personal data in specific cases;
  * Receive your personal data in a machine-readable format and send it to another controller (known as 'data portability');
  * Request that decisions based on automated processing concerning you or significantly affecting you and based on your personal data are made by real people, not only by computers. You also have the right in this case to express your point of view and to contest the decision.

### Contact Us: 

If you have any questions, need to request GDPR-compliant data removal, or would like more information please reach out to us at [gdpr@getvideostream.com](mailto:team@getvideostream.com).
